THILAK RAMANIE SHANMUGASUNDARAM

Email | Mobile | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

MSc in Computing candidate with an expected 2:1 degree, with 3+ years of hands-on experience in Software development, specializing in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, and Angular, coupled with proficiency in testing tools like Selenium and Testcomplete. Open for Front-end / Full-stack Developer role from July 2024, seeking Stamp-1/1G visa sponsorship.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer (part-time) @Harrier Systems

10/2023 - Present

- Rapidly developing UI solutions using React and Angular framework.
- Implemented a streamlined user authentication and onboarding process on a law firm's website, reducing the registration steps by 30%, resulted in a 25% increase in user sign-ups within the first month.

Software Developer @ScribeEMR technology services private limited

01/2023 - 08/2023

- Implemented React.js UI to enhance medical application accessibility, integrating a cutting-edge rich text editor and speech-to-text functionality; boosted user engagement by 20%.
- Spearheaded and managed frontend development project from inception, leading a team of 2 developers
- Improved UI and resolved bugs in a medical app with Angular, optimizing performance, and contributed to the hiring process as a technical interviewer.

Frameworks & Tools used: React.js, Angular, NodeJS, MongoDB, AWS, Azure, Figma

Freelance web developer @International food ingredients trading co

12/2022 - 01/2023

• Freelanced to develop a React.js web app for iFit, a spice trading company, meeting industry-specific needs. Project Here

Software Developer @Siemens technology services private limited

12/2021 - 12/2022

- Engineered the Angular-based user interface for a load management system, featuring a sophisticated dashboard implementation for enhanced data visualization and user interaction.
- Created an API using Express, Node.js, and AWS to support the dynamic load management system, enhancing its functionality and performance.
- Provided crucial support to the firmware development team by troubleshooting errors in a third-party plugin, ensuring the seamless integration of external components.

Achievements: Integrated a non-authorization plugin in Versicharge at Siemens, introducing a key feature and advancing the system.

Frameworks & Tools used: React.js, Angular, NodeJS, AWS, Figma, OCPP-NG, Python, Syslog-NG

- Established Selenium and Java framework for efficient web application testing, streamlining processes.
- Designed Test Complete and Python framework for desktop apps, contributing to comprehensive testing strategies and driving continuous improvement in testing methodologies.
- Presented multiple ideas to enhance test scripts for web applications, demonstrating a commitment to continuous improvement in testing methodologies.

Achievements: Attained a significant milestone by developing a smart script during my employment at Aptean, showcasing innovation and expertise in test script development.

Languages & Tools used: Java, Selenium, Python, Testcomplete, Test execute, MS Excel

EDUCATION

MSc in Computing (Expected Grade: 2:1)	09/2023 - Present
Dublin City University, Ireland	
BTech in Information Technology (CGPA: 8.51)	06/2017 - 05/2021
Thiagarajar college of Engineering, India	

SKILLS

•	React.js	•	Angular	•	Node.js
•	Bootstrap	•	Figma	•	AWS
•	NoSQL	•	Java	•	Python

ACHIEVEMENTS

2018	• Runner of front-end development event at MIT, Chennai				
	 Winner of poster presentation in Elixir 				
2019	Winner of poster presentation in Elixir				
2020	Winner of CERTATIM an inter-department hackathon.				
	• Winner of Appathon 2K20, an event where we developed a CMS for the MP,				
	Madurai				

CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy:

React
Angular
JavaScript
Flutter
Bootstrap 4
CSS
Front-End
Front-End
CSS

Coursera:

• Arduino and C Programming

• IOT and Embedded Systems

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

• Dancing - Was the **General Secretary** of AFD hip-hop crew during my bachelors and a member of DCU dance society currently.